In this video, I'd like to talk
a bit about the GNOME Display manager.
So how about display managers? Well,
GNOME or GNOME is a display manager.
It's the most commonly used display manager
on Linux and as such it provides a
graphical interface for which programs can be
started in Windows or multiple virtual desktops.
So GNOME is the most used display manager. Other display
managers are available as well, such as kde. The fact is
that GNOME is used on Red Hat as well as
on Ubuntu. So in this video we'll focus on GNOME only.
Now, working with differences between
display managers should be relatively easy
as it is all about
clicking the appropriate graphical element.
First thing you need to do before you
can work with the graphical interface is login.
To do so, the GDM or GNOME Display Manager
process is used. It's a bit confusing because the
GNOME Display Manager is the name for the entire
graphical packet, but also for the thing that takes
care of logins. Specifically, GDM by default will
show users that have been defined on the system.
And to login as a non
listed user, click the other item.
That shouldn't be necessary too
often because GDM is pretty
well capable of picking up
your current existing user accounts.
After logging in, you will
get access to the GNOME shell.
Let
me demonstrate.
So here you can see what the
GDM login looks like and it's prompting
for the password for the currently
only existing user on this Ubuntu system.
So let me enter
the password and then
it's bringing me
to the GNOME shell.
So this is the very first time I'm starting this
interface. So this is giving the welcome to Ubuntu. I don't
like this welcome to Ubuntu. So I'm clicking over it
and then we see what the interface is looking like.
Now you might notice that the look and
feel of this GNOME shell in Ubuntu is
slightly different from the way it shows
on CentOS, but the key elements are there.
The thing that is different is that Ubuntu is
using this sidebar with a couple of commonly used applications.
And on CentOS you just have
the menu in the upper left corner.
So you click the menu and then you
get access to the bar where you can
search the application that you want to work
with. More about that in the next videos.